Tyler J. Roberts

(262) 388-4050 | tjroberts314@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyleroberts | https://github.com/tyler314

Summary

Software engineer with 6+ years experience in development and design. My most recent work has been well-balanced between building back-end systems, and front-end web applications.

Skills: agile, amazon web services (aws), api, ci/cd pipelines, css, databases, docker, express, git, grafana, html, java, javascript, jira, kafka, kotlin, kubernetes, linux, nodejs, project management, python, reactjs, scrum, seo, sql, typescript, version control

Experience

Software Engineer & Project Manager

Copper + Honey Salon \cdot Freelance

Feb 2023 - Present · Remote

- https://www.copperandhoneysalon.com
- Designed fully functional website from scratch, using AWS tools to quickly launch in time for the client's grand opening.
- Leveraged SEO techniques resulting in the website rising to the top Google Search results for hair extensions in the local area. Consistently receiving 300+ clicks/month.
- Designed solution for clients to edit their employee info on their site at any time, seamlessly working across all screen sizes.
- Work directly with the owners and an independent UX Designer, in order to design software solutions, create timelines, and conduct demos.
- Tools & Technologies: AWS, Javascript, React.js, Material UI, SEO.

Software Engineer

Warner Bros. Discovery · Contract

 $Mar 2023 - Dec 2023 \cdot Remote$

- Became key team contributor within first month by quickly becoming a part of on-call rotations, contributing to code reviews, and pushing code, allowing our team to meet the MAX launch deadline in May.
- Led efforts of designing novel integration tests, and setting up new Grafana monitoring + alerts for the team's new MAX services, in order to meet company SLA requirements.
- Lead engineer tasked with onboarding a new service from a re-org. Required collaboration with three away teams, to understand the service and get it running before my contract's end.
- General Operational Excellence. Ran load tests, contributed to new documentation, scrum leader, etc.
- $-\ Tools\ \&\ Technologies:\ AWS,\ Typescript,\ Node. js,\ Express. js,\ Kafka,\ Grafana,\ Kubernetes\ +\ Dockernetes\ +\ Doc$

Software Engineer

Amazon.com · Full-Time

Dec 2019 – Jan 2023 · Seattle, WA

- Designed adapted responses for Smart Home requests. Features such as sharing customer insights, listing device capabilities, and a "Good Morning / Night" experience.
- Delivered Brief / Verbose Mode for ACMS. Developed filtering logic to serve personalized responses based on the individual customer's device setting.
- Migrated all Alexa personality content from a legacy CMS, to ACMS/ARMS. Three month endeavor that required the development of bulk migration scripts, working closely with a select few engineers, PMs, and content creators across all supported locales.
- Led the org in hiring engineers by conducting over 50 interviews in Q1 2022, resulting in a higher head count for hiring. Received the quarterly award for this effort.
- Social chair for the org, responsible for organizing quarterly events during the pandemic remote period, encouraging teammates to socialize and get to know each other better.
- Tools & Technologies: AWS, Kotlin, Javascript, React.js, CI/CD Code Pipelines, Git

Software Engineer

Cockroach Labs · Full-Time

May 2019 − Sep 2019 · New York, NY

Cockroach Labs

- Apart of the Bulk I/O team, responsible for bulk operations in the database, including backup and restore, and schema changes in the database.
- Fixed issue where the dump operation would include interleaved table statements inside of create table statements, causing dependency issues upon a restore.
- Designed features for the backup & restore process to include additional metadata about the cluster. Required a redesign of how the process worked, and reduced manual steps by the user.
- Tools & Technologies: Golang, SQL, Git/Github.

Software Engineer

Dataminr · Full-Time

Sep 2018 – Feb 2019 · New York, NY

- Worked on developing the tools used to search and filter through the Twitter pipeline and other media sources.
- JVM code base comprised of Scala and Java, with an AWS infrastructure. Kinesis used for processing the large data sources, where S3 was used to store the raw data.
- Migrated Pastebin data source from Kinesis to Kafka. Involved dependencies between several teams, and required collaboration among them.
- Tools & Technologies: Scala, Java, Maven, Docker, AWS, Google Guice, Git/Gitlab, IntelliJ, MacOS.

Software Engineer

IBM Corporation · Full-Time

Jul 2017 – Aug 2019 · Yorktown Heights, NY

- Developed Python application in collaboration with sister team that moved locally stored data and user accounts to Bluemix, IBM's cloud platform as a service.
- Designed and engineered a web application from the ground up using HTML, CSS, Angular, and Bootstrap. Responsible for the front-end, including page navigation using an MVC design pattern.
- Used Docker to rigorously test the deployment of the web application onto the servers.
- Tools & Technologies: Python, Docker, HTML, Angular, Javascript, PyCharm, MacOS.

Education

B.S. Computer Engineering, Computer Science, & Mathematics with Physics Certificate (minor). University of Wisconsin - Madison, May 2017